♪ Music ♪
Good evening to all the listeners of J-WAVE WOW MUSIC.
My name is Seisaku, I sing and play bass in Mongol 800.
This week, we have started again.
WOW MUSIC, a music discussion among creators.
Last week we welcomed Kenta from Wanima.
Today, we welcome Ayunidi of Vish as our guest,
Today, we would like to bring you a late-night music discussion with Ayunidi from Vish.
The more I look into Ayunidi, the more I find out that she has a mysterious charm.
The more I look into Ayunidi, the more I find out about her, the more I want to dig deeper into her.
JWAVE WOW MUSICToday we welcome Ayunidi from BISH. Please give her my best regards.
My name is Iunidi from BISH. I'm Iunidi from BISH, and it's been a long time.
It's been a while.
It has been a long time.
It's been a long time.
I'm nervous. Me too. No, no, no, why are you nervous?
I'm more nervous than you. No, no, no.
But I was surprised to see you, you know, just the other day, you know. Yes, just the other day.
BiSH project. Yes.
For the event at Kagao. Yes.
Seisaku's solo. Yes.
A little bit at Cleré Gypsy.
I was invited. The two of us were able to go to Mombishi, which we had longed for. No, no, no, no, no, no, welcome back.
I was surprised because I didn't think that you would accept me already. I didn't think you would even do a session. I was very happy to be able to do it.
I'd like to talk a little bit about the pattern, or rather, the memories of that session, while digging back a little bit.
I would like to talk about various things related to music today, but first I would like to ask you about your musical roots,
When did you first become interested in music?
When did you become interested in music?
It's really only recently, in the last few years.
After I joined Bishu and started working as a solo artist
I became more conscious of music for the first time.
I became more conscious of music.
To put it another way, before that, did you have any image of what music was?
No, I really didn't have any exposure to music or art when I was a child.
I played the piano a little bit when I was little.
But I was so scared of the teacher that I didn't want to go.
I would walk in the door and say I didn't want to go, and just quit.
Looking back, I really wish I had continued.
I think I really should have kept going.
I think I should have kept playing piano, but I had already given up on it.
I had an impression that I didn't like music at all.
I didn't listen to or watch anything, or have a favorite artist, or anything like that.
I didn't have a favorite artist or anything like that, I just listened to what was popular at school and heard it on the school broadcasts.
I only knew of bands that were really popular. I wanted to be an architect in the past.
An architect? I see.
I didn't know any music at all, but I had a feeling for Mr. Monpachi since I was a little kid.
It's played at school, right? I knew it, I knew it so well.
It's like a part of life.
Wait a minute. Let's get this straight.
I'm sorry.
I just saw the word "architecture" and it just popped out.
That's probably where I got the most out of it.
But that too has fallen by the wayside.
That's why I became a bish.
No, no, no.
It's interesting to see the video, but...
It's interesting to watch the video.
It's interesting to listen to it, but...
I'm sorry.
I wonder how you joined Bish.
My sister is a big fan of Bisch.
She used to travel all over the country for live shows.
But the girl who was her sister's favorite
The girl who was her favorite quit the group.
I saw on the internet that they were looking for a new member
I applied for the audition and I got it.
And I got it.
Are you the most excited one?
Yes, I am.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I still understand it pretty well.
When did you want to become an architect?
When I was in high school.
When you were a student?
That's right.
I was learning how to build and design houses.
I was studying house building and design.
My hometown is in Hokkaido.
But when I was accepted into the fine arts program
I came to Tokyo.
From what you've said so far...
Is that why you started playing an instrument recently?
Yes, that's right.
I haven't sung for a few years.
I don't sing.
Really?
That's funny.
Can I ask you about one of your influences?
Tattoo Alley by Number Girl.
When I was doing my solo, I picked up my first instrument.
I was playing bass.
I invited Hisako Tabuchi of Number Girl to be my support guitarist.
She accepted my offer.
I met Hisako and she was a big part of my life.
That's why I chose this song.
Next, I would like to ask you about your live performances.
Bish is all about live performance.
Thank you very much.
Do you remember your first live performance after joining Bish?Do you remember your first live performance after joining Bish?
Yes, I do.
It was our debut live at ZEPP Tokyo.
It was a free concert.
It was a free live concert.
The last song was the unveiling of the new members.
The last song was the first song we played with the current 6 members.
It was called "Spark".
I was so nervous!
My armpits were all sweaty.
I was shaking.
My voice was shaking as we performed the song.
Just this one song at the show.
That was the first day, wasn't it?
But a few days later, we started a national tour.
With Bish, you're singing and dancing.
It's different from playing an instrument.
I didn't have to worry about playing the wrong song.
Well, I see.
I'm trying to do my best with the songs for now.
That's amazing!
It's quite nerve-wracking, though, isn't it?
What's more...
Yes, it is.
It's really the first time to perform live... or rather, to show it off to everyone.
That's almost true.
I opened a Twitter account about a month ago as a new member.
I opened a Twitter account about a month ago.
But I don't want to show my face unless I have more than 15,000 followers.
I was bish to do it in a way that I wouldn't show my face unless I had over 15,000 followers.
I was doing a Bish thing.
And 15,000?
I think I went over 15,000 right away.
And then, I'd show a little glimpse of my face.
Just a glimpse.
As you know, Mr. Seisaku.
Bish is a very unique group of people.
I didn't talk to most of the members at the first show.
I was scared at the time.
How did you blend in?
No, it's just recently.
Of course.
It takes time, doesn't it?
What a surprise.
Members...
It's not easy to do things in a straight line, but you seem to be able to get through it with a smile.
It's hard to make a simple fix, but they seem to be able to get through it without a hitch.
The house and
Bisch is always associated with live performances.
I don't care if it's something you're aware of as Bisch, or if it's something you think of as Bisch.
What are you personally conscious of as a bish?
I think that live performances are the best place to show how you live your life.
I often put too much effort into every single moment in interviews, radio and TV.
I often put too much effort into every moment in interviews, on the radio, or on TV, but in a live performance, I feel I can be myself the most.
Bisch, each of you is a unique human being, and each of you has your own unique view of the world.
Each bish is a unique human being, and we respect each other's unique worldview.
I think it's a good thing that we don't interfere too much with each other while respecting each other's unique view of the world.
I think that's one of the best things about Bisch.
I think it's in the live performance that we can fully add this to the band.
I wasn't singing with an instrument because I had a passion for music.
I was aiming for architecture, and then suddenly I took a sharp turn and joined Bisch.
And now live performance is the way to go... it's really amazing!
It took me 6 years!
It took me 6 years to get here, but I'm very much in tune with myself now.
If I can say that, it's probably because
I'm sure I've done a lot of stupid things.
There are a lot of simple changes.
I couldn't distinguish the sound at all at first.
I couldn't tell which was the guitar sound and which was the drum sound...
But as I fell in love with music and started playing my own instruments
And as I started to play instruments and create things, I started to understand how the guitar sounded.
I started to understand how the guitar sounded in this song.
I started to understand what the guitar sounded like, and I started to enjoy the live performance more and more.
Can you tell us about one song that you thought was great at a live performance by an artist you've seen?
I'd like to know if there is one song that you thought was great at a live performance by an artist you've seen.
It's called "Mono no Kojo" and it's called "Heterojin".
I recently had the chance to see the band Mono no Kojo live at Liquid
I saw them live at Liquid.
It's like a dream you have when you have the flu.
Like a dream you have when you have the flu.
Chaotic, a little bit eerie
A little bit eerie, a little bit funny...
I was really struck by the fact that Bisch could never produce that kind of feeling.
It's funny, I'd like to hear just what you think of it now.
There were clowns and such in the production.
The world view was really cool!
I'd like to focus a little bit on your songwriting.
I'd like to focus on your songwriting.
And as a solo artist, there is Pedro.
Is there a difference in your creative activities?
Yes, there are.
I don't really think of myself as doing one thing this way and another thing that way.
I'm not conscious of doing this one this way or that one that way.
I'm just a woman.
I'm a woman, so my work reflects my life and what I've noticed before Unity.
I'm a woman, so what I've done in my life and what I've realized before Unity is reflected naturally in both of them.
In terms of music, I have a solo band project called Pedro.
I have my own instruments there.
I also compose my own music.
So the sense of songwriting is completely different.
With Vish, I think I'd like to sing with all six of us.I think I'd like to sing with the six of us in Vish.
I want to put words into it.
With Pedro, I want to sing about my own life.
or stories that I've made up on my own.
I can sing whatever I want without being shy.
I can sing by myself without worrying about anything else.
I think I can write without worrying about anything else.
When did you start writing lyrics?
I started writing lyrics about 6 years ago when I joined Vish.
That's when I started writing lyrics for the first time.
I started composing about 3 years ago when I started pedro.
I started composing when I started to play an instrument.
Did you choose a bass instrument out of the blue?
Oh, that's right.
The reason why I started playing solo is because the president of Vish's office asked me out of the blue.
The president of Vish's office called me out of the blue.
After Vish's concert, he asked me if I wanted to play solo.
He asked Ayu if she wanted to play with a band.
But the boss said if he wanted to do it, he should do it.
Before I could say "I can't do it if I don't have an instrument"...
He suggested that if I wanted to play an instrument, I should play the guitar or bass guitar.
A guitar has six strings and a bass has four.
I thought I'd take the bass, so I took the easy way out and chose it.
I think it's a choice that will get you into the swamp, for better or worse.
I think that choosing a bass guitar will be a long-term relationship in your musical life!
And from the standpoint of writing the music, I chose the bass guitar.
I chose it for some reason.
But originally, I think there are a lot of things that are working in my head, like the way I build the music.
I think there is something else going on in my head.
I think it will be more interesting to create music
I think it's interesting now.
It's interesting.
I chose the bass guitar with a really random idea at first, but
but now I really like it.
And with Music Man's bass again
That's right.
It's crazy!
And Mr. Tabuchi, the guitarist, he's badass, isn't he?
He's so good!
When I heard Pedro's music
I was a little shocked.
Thank you very much.
I thought it was simply cool.
No, no, no, thank you very much.
Thank you very much.
There are punk bands that don't have instruments.
I thought the Pedlow one was very rock 'n' roll.
I thought Pedro was very rock 'n' roll, and I didn't aim for anything.
They can show many different colors and expressions.
I think it's a possibility.
The music I make and the songs that go along with it.
I think the songs are also important to me.
I choose all the words myself.
I think it's something that can only be done by you.
I simply wanted to see that live performance.
Really?
I thought it was really cool.
Tabuji's guitar intro and all.
They are a great rock band!
Really...
I thought I liked a lot of their songs.
Really?
I took the opportunity to listen to them.
Thank you very much.
You're making music at a crazy pace, aren't you? I'm sorry.
I've been working on it.
I'm a bit of a glitch now.
I think I've already released three albums in about three years.
I've got another one coming out in 2020 and another one in 2009.
It's Ren-chan.
I thought your choice of words was excellent.
I like the way you put titles on your albums.
Thank you very much.
It's a reaction to the fact that we didn't write together.
I don't know, the way it's rebounding... it's amazing.
Maybe for the first time after listening to this radio
I.M.D. girl in the bish.
I think a lot of people are surprised when they focus on one person.
I think there are many people who are surprised.
I'm one of them.
She's so cool and her world view is so cool.
I don't know what it is, but if someone were to show it to me without hesitation
I think everyone would be envious of that musician who can't write a song and is always complaining.
I think everyone would be envious.
But in a good sense, there are no restrictions on the act of creating something that started from scratch.
There are no restrictions.
In that sense, I think I'm able to create freely.
How do you feel like you can express yourself like this?
When I was in Vish.
I was very blessed to be able to work in such an environment.
The songs were written in perfect conditions.
I didn't know the process of making something from zero to one at all.
So when I did it for the first time as a solo artist
I realized how difficult it is to make music.
I was almost frustrated at first
I almost gave up on it at first, but I learned about the pain of making music.
But I learned the pain of making music, but also the joy and happiness and feeling of pleasure that goes beyond the pain.
I learned the pain of making music, but I also learned the joy and happiness and feeling of the joy beyond the pain of making music.
It was easy for me to realize that there is no right answer.
That's why it was easy for me to put words to music.That's why I've been able to put words to music.
I used to be hesitant or reserved in putting words to music.
But that has completely disappeared.
The other day, when I had a chance to talk with Mombish, he told me that he had written a song with a small voice.
I asked him when he wrote the song about the little voice.
I was surprised to hear you say, "When I was 18? I was so surprised to hear you say that you were 18 years old.
I thought, "How can you write a song like this at that age?
Yes, but in a good way.
Ignorance, selflessness.
I don't really feel like I'm making music.
The volume of the first A-melody and the volume of the second A-melody
So they're different sizes.
I see.
The novel is totally different.
That's why I put the lyrics first and stretch them out.
Oh, I see.
And I don't know the key or how to make it.
There was a mysterious grouping that the person who made the song sang it.
When I had to name my own key key.
I thought, "I'm going to sing while playing, so it has to be easy to play.
I thought it should be around here.
Like 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7...
And then I started singing from there.
I think I made the basic melody.
And then the melody and the bass.
I would say, "This is what it sounds like," and then the chords would be a little bit minor, and so on.
We were a band, so we didn't use minor chords and everything was done with power chords, so the process of completion was a lot of fun.
The process of creating a new instrument or something like that.
I understood the feeling that if you say it's finished, then it's finished.
I think it's different to make a song like that just because everyone recognized it.
I've been saying for a long time that I'll never be able to write a song like that again.
That's why I sing it every time.
When I sing a song like that, I can instantly go back to the time when I wrote it, to that feeling...
That's why...
I think it's better to write more and more songs as they come to my mind.
I think it's better to make more and more songs as they come to you.
There are things that can only be made on initial impulse.
You can look back and laugh about it later.
I thought that it would be good if I could enjoy myself from today.
Up to now
Are there any songs that you have made or sung that hold special memories for you?
Yes, the song "Beginning, End and Beginning" by Bish. I wrote the lyrics to this song, and it tells the story of the birth of Bish and the present.
I have written many songs about myself as a solo artist, but I have not written many songs about Bish as a noun.
So I wrote a song about the place where Bish was born, and also a song about what it's like to be one of the six of us.
Speaking of Bish, it was announced that the band will disband in 2023.
How do you feel nowadays? I think it's been a long but short half year.
I think it's been a long time, but it's been a very short time.
The fact that it was only inside Bish was only announced half a year ago this year.
It was a little bit easier for me to accept the fact that it was a matter of fact for all the fans and people who knew Bisho.
I feel a little more at ease now.
Really...
Before, I used to think that we were going to break up in my mind when we were performing live.
But in front of the audience, I couldn't be so sad and they didn't know.
I felt like I was lying a little.
I felt like I was doing something I shouldn't have done, but after we announced the breakup this year
After we announced the breakup of the group this year, I started to think about what I would eat and when I would die.
But since the announcement of our breakup this year, there is a big difference between eating a meal after you know when you're going to die and eating a meal when you don't know when you're going to die.
I want to cherish and treasure each day.
I know that.
But I've become more aware of that.
I think that each live performance is not really a matter of course.
The people I met when I joined B magazine
I'm starting to feel more and more that it's really a miracle that I've met the people I've met since I joined B magazine.
I've become more aware that I want to express my love and gratitude to the people who helped raise VCIO and to the people who helped me find VCIO.
I'm touring now, aren't I?
You announced the tour last year on December 24th?
Yes, December 24th.
So there was a trend of Kohaku.
The new year started, but I still had a lot of gigs going on.
It's like Bish in the sense that you are running through your busy schedule.
I guess it's just like Bish.
And I think it's also a bit like Bish to not stop for live shows.
I feel like I'm doing my duty to the customers.
It's probably a lot of work just to do that.
And you're also doing live shows and releasing 12 months of music.
Thank you very much.
We're actually on two tours right now.
That's right.
One is a tour of prefectures I've never been to before, and the other is a tour of live houses I've been to before.
And another tour where we're going to visit the live houses that we've visited so far.
And we're also going to release 12 months in a row.
I made a promise when I announced this tour, that I would release 12 months in a row.
I'm going to go on tour every month, and as soon as I get home, I'm going to shoot a music video and record it.
I'm going to shoot a music video and record it
I've been shooting music videos, recording them, and shooting them tomorrow.
It's too intense, too fast-paced.
I'm still in a state of emotional instability, or rather, I'm in a state of great joy, sorrow, and happiness.
I'm in full bloom every day, aren't I?
I know, right?
I can't feel any Hitaro-like moments at the moment.
Well, I think it's going to be a year of gaining something different in the midst of the dizzying amount of information
I think it's going to be a year of gaining something different.
I'm sure each stage will feel different.
I'm going to be so sad when I can count backwards.
Maybe the second half of this or something.
Even at this point, I think it might be the last time I can go to a B-Scene concert.
I think there are some customers who might not be able to go to the B-Scene show for the last time.
That's very thoughtful.
I want as many people as possible to see the show.
I'm sure they want as many people to see the show as possible.I'm sure there is a desire to be seen.
And I think that's one of the reasons for the consecutive releases.
Even though he said it's going to end, he's already started to create new songs.
I wonder what this is.
It's the same with the energy that goes the other way.
Last month's release was also the longest ever.
That's right.
No matter how you change, no matter how I change
Tomorrow will come, to meet you
I'm going to call it Donkimi for short
Seriously? It's so short!
Tomorrow's set includes Don Kimi, right?
Don't say "Don't worry"!
I won't introduce the song "Don't worry".
Can I use someone else's?
If you chew, you'll be punished.
May I say something?
No matter how much you change, I wonder what I'll be like tomorrow
I made a mistake.
You made a mistake?
It's a game of punishment.
It's difficult.
This song has the highest BPM in the history of Pish.
I haven't sung many ballads in my career.
I think this song will show a new face in this 12 consecutive month release.
Some of the titles are the longest ever.
See You" will be released on July 27th!
What kind of song is this new song?
This song is really a song about Bish and his current situation.
The lyrics of this song are very personal to me.
There is a song by Asem for Bisch called "On a night when the stars are twinkling", and I quoted the words of the song.
and the lyrics are quoted from the song.
We know we're going to say goodbye
It's a song about the light that is still inside of us.
The time went by so fast!
We still have a lot to talk about!
But it's time to say goodbye
It was announced that the group will break up in 2023.
There was not a hint of sentimentality in what they said.
I even feel that you are challenging new things more and more
I even feel that you are taking on new challenges more and more.
If you could tell us about a moment in your life when you feel happy to be doing music again, could you?
Yes, I do.
But now that we are able to play live...
But the situation in the world is still like a corona disaster.
The audience can't speak and they have to wear masks.
I can tell when the audience is crying.
I can also tell when they are happy or laughing.
But nowadays, with the development of youth
The other day, I was on tour, and after the tour, I opened Twitter before going to bed at a hotel in a rural area, I couldn't stop crying when I saw that. It's not often in life that someone says something like that to you,
But we also feel the same way about our fans who are smiling at us,
I also have many experiences of being saved by music, having come to love music after encountering it,
But I have also learned that it is people who make music, and that is the fundamental love of music,
I have learned that the people who make music are human beings, and that without that love, nothing I do will ever be good enough,
That feeling took root in me, and I wanted to keep working hard and sweating as hard as I had until the breakup,
I would like to continue to work hard and sweat as hard as I have until the breakup, and express my love and gratitude to everyone.
I think words are important, as only Japanese people can do,
But at the very end, I was a bit sad.
I was finally able to soak it all in.
But, yes, we all play music and bish on stage, and we may be on the side of delivering it,
But of course, we are the ones who can receive the music, and we are saying that we are going to bring it to 2023,
I think it's okay to receive as much as you want.
I think it would be good to travel around the country and receive a lot of gifts from your fans and those who have helped you a lot.
Thank you very much.
No, no, no, it was nice to talk to you again.
I play bass and sing for Mongolian 800.
Seisaku has been navigating.
How was WOW MUSIC?
There was a lot of content that I couldn't listen to if I tried.
I was really able to talk about that mysterious charm of Einreicher,
It was that kind of time that I still have not heard enough.
Our next guest will be Mr. Ken Yokoyama.
It is well known that we love and copy his music.
Ken is the guitarist of High Standard.
He is also very active as a solo artist and the president of Visal Breath,
He is also the president of Visal Breath,
As far as I can imagine, there will be almost no talk about music.
I am looking forward to it.
Well, I am looking forward to it,
I look forward to it, and I hope you all look forward to it.
See you next week at this time.
Our partner up to this point has been the Mongolian 800 Seisaku.